<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fune_Macato_Project</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fishing_etiquette">FishingEtiquette</string>
    <string name="fishing_guidebook">Fishing Guidebook</string>
    <string name="how_to_fish">How to Fish</string>
    <string name="equipment">Equipment</string>
    <string name="fishing_etiquette">Fishing Etiquette</string>
    <string name="unsafe_fishing">Unsafe Fishing</string>
    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="preparing_to_fish">Preparing to Fish</string>
    <string name="going_fishing">Going Fishing</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_preparing_to_fish">PreparingToFish</string>
    <string name="there_are_plenty_of_fish_in_the_sea_but_finding_the_right_area_could_mean_more_specific_catches_better_catching_probability_or_even_a_friendlier_community_to_help_enjoy_the_trip">There are plenty of fish in the sea, but finding the right area could mean more specific catches, better catching probability, or even a friendlier community to help enjoy the trip.</string>
    <string name="for_people_who_live_on_the_coast_saltwater_fishing_is_an_easy_pick_for_them_they_will_probably_already_have_several_poplar_sites_around_them_generally_the_most_popular_among_them_would_be_a_great_place_to_start_as_it_would_have_the_most_community_built_around_it_as_well_as_contain_a_probable_good_fish_population">For people who live on the coast, saltwater fishing is an easy pick for them. They will probably already have several poplar sites around them. Generally the most popular among them would be a great place to start as it would have the most community built around it as well as contain a probable good fish population.</string>
    <string name="for_the_more_landlocked_areas_finding_a_spot_may_just_involve_asking_around_with_locals_or_at_fishing_shops_of_any_kind_people_who_regularly_fish_tend_to_be_very_friendly_and_eager_to_show_what_they_know_to_beginners">For the more landlocked areas, finding a spot may just involve asking around with locals or at fishing shops of any kind. People who regularly fish tend to be very friendly and eager to show what they know to beginners.</string>
    <string name="_1_research_areas_for_fishing">1.) Research areas for Fishing:</string>
    <string name="_2_investigate_good_times_to_go_fishing">2.) Investigate good times to go Fishing:</string>
    <string name="after_you_ve_found_a_place_the_timing_should_be_accounted_for_as_well_for_example_plenty_of_people_tend_to_fish_around_dawn_or_dusk_as_these_are_peak_feeding_times_for_fish">After you\'ve found a place, the timing should be accounted for as well. For example, plenty of people tend to fish around dawn or dusk as these are peak feeding times for fish.</string>
    <string name="textview">TextView</string>
    <string name="_3_make_sure_you_have_the_permissions_needed">3.) Make sure you have the permissions needed:</string>
    <string name="however_many_more_private_or_commercial_fishing_areas_exist_where_admission_is_charged_in_order_to_enter_and_fish_these_such_places_include_that_permission_within_their_cost_making_them_cheaper_than_a_license_for_occasional_trips">However, many more private or commercial fishing areas exist where admission is charged in order to enter and fish. These such places include that permission within their cost, making them cheaper than a license for occasional trips.</string>
    <string name="localized_fishing_licenses_are_required_in_order_to_fish_and_take_your_catch_home_these_licenses_can_be_obtained_from_local_department_of_fish_and_wildlife_centers">Localized fishing licenses are required in order to fish and take your catch home. These licenses can be obtained from local Department of Fish and Wildlife centers</string>
    <string name="_4_grab_the_right_reel_and_rod_for_you">4.) Grab the right reel and rod for you:</string>
    <string name="as_long_as_the_line_is_medium_in_length_and_flexible_it_should_do_fine_for_beginners_for_now_these_details_shouldn_t_concern_you_too_much_until_you_enjoy_the_sport_are_familiar_with_it_and_are_ready_to_invest_in_better_equipment_for_now_the_basics_will_do_just_fine">As long as the line is medium in length and flexible, it should do fine for beginners. For now, these details shouldn\'t concern you too much until you enjoy the sport, are familiar with it, and are ready to invest in better equipment. For now, the basics will do just fine.</string>
    <string name="prices_will_vary_but_getting_the_rod_from_a_regular_big_box_retailer_would_probably_do_you_much_more_than_going_to_a_specialty_store_try_to_get_a_bundle_that_comes_with_its_own_reel_and_tackle_box_as_you_can_use_these_to_learn_which_tools_you_want_to_use_continuously">Prices will vary, but getting the rod from a regular big-box retailer would probably do you much more than going to a specialty store. Try to get a bundle that comes with its own reel and tackle box as you can use these to learn which tools you want to use continuously.</string>
    <string name="as_for_bait_live_fake_and_dead_bait_are_all_options_for_you_to_buy_these_are_all_fine_for_now_as_you_will_eventually_learn_how_to_use_other_tools_to_catch_your_own_bait_later_in_addition_it_is_useful_to_get_over_any_squeamishness_on_dead_bait_before_you_move_on_to_live_bait">As for bait, live, fake, and dead bait are all options for you to buy. These are all fine for now as you will eventually learn how to use other tools to catch your own bait later. In addition, it is useful to get over any squeamishness on dead bait before you move on to live bait.</string>
    <string name="if_you_are_going_to_be_using_live_bait_be_aware_of_the_need_to_contain_them_in_some_sort_of_storage_and_keep_them_alive_by_either_cycling_water_within_the_storage_or_using_an_air_pump_to_pump_oxygen_back_into_the_water_otherwise_the_bait_will_die_in_several_minutes">If you are going to be using live bait, be aware of the need to contain them in some sort of storage and keep them alive by either cycling water within the storage or using an air pump to pump oxygen back into the water. Otherwise, the bait will die in several minutes.</string>
    <string name="_5_prepare_your_bait">5.) Prepare your bait:</string>
    <string name="button">Button</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="_1_prepare_your_line">1.) Prepare your line.</string>
    <string name="preparing_your_line_with_the_appropriate_bait_and_tools_can_take_some_time_to_learn_as_different_items_have_different_uses_and_knowing_which_to_use_takes_some_familiarity_with_their_effects_on_the_line">Preparing your line with the appropriate bait and tools can take some time to learn as different items have different uses and knowing which to use takes some familiarity with their effects on the line.</string>
    <string name="tying_the_knots_in_lines_may_require_some_certain_special_kinds_of_knots_a_basic_one_that_is_useful_to_learn_as_well_as_easy_is_the_j_knot_which_can_be_best_learned_with_a_short_supplemental_video_tutorial_search_sinkers_or_weights_are_used_to_give_the_line_more_inertia_against_currents_in_order_to_sop_your_hook_from_just_floating_on_the_surface">Tying the knots in lines may require some certain special kinds of knots. A basic one that is useful to learn as well as easy is the J knot, which can be best learned with a short supplemental video tutorial search. Sinkers, or weights, are used to give the line more inertia against currents in order to sop your hook from just floating on the surface.</string>
    <string name="bobbers_are_used_for_visibly_seeing_your_line_and_any_potential_bites_tugging_down_on_it_baiting_a_hook_may_not_be_the_most_pleasant_task_but_bait_should_usually_be_hooked_several_times_for_security_however_it_should_look_natural_as_animals_would_not_aim_for_dead_looking_fish_and_like_to_only_bite_live_looking_bait">Bobbers are used for visibly seeing your line and any potential bites tugging down on it. Baiting a hook may not be the most pleasant task, but bait should usually be hooked several times for security. However, it should look natural as animals would not aim for dead looking fish and like to only bite live-looking bait.</string>
    <string name="_2_cast_the_line">2.) Cast the line.</string>
    <string name="for_both_the_main_types_of_reels_the_technique_is_the_same_both_reels_have_a_locked_and_released_phase_for_its_line_the_general_technique_is_to_unlock_the_line_and_hold_it_with_your_fingers_and_then_swing_your_rod_in_an_arc_letting_go_of_the_line_at_the_peak_of_the_arc_the_momentum_should_cause_the_hook_if_it_s_heavy_enough_to_fly_as_it_sinks_the_line_should_be_locked_as_to_not_let_the_string_fall_loose_around_the_real_or_to_let_a_fish_just_walk_away_with_your_hook">For both the main types of reels, the technique is the same. Both reels have a locked and released phase for its line. The general technique is to unlock the line and hold it with your fingers and then swing your rod in an arc, letting go of the line at the peak of the arc. The momentum should cause the hook (if it\'s heavy enough) to fly. As it sinks, the line should be locked as to not let the string fall loose around the real or to let a fish just walk away with your hook.</string>
    <string name="_3_wait_for_a_fish">3.) Wait for a fish.</string>
    <string name="patience_is_a_well_known_attribute_to_fishing_but_is_a_bit_exaggerated_don_t_be_impatient_with_your_rod_after_about_leaving_it_for_about_15_minutes_it_is_a_good_idea_to_take_it_out_and_recast_it_it_may_need_to_be_baited_again_so_leaving_it_in_longer_than_that_could_be_a_waste_of_time">Patience is a well-known attribute to fishing, but is a bit exaggerated. Don\'t be impatient with your rod, after about leaving it for about 15 minutes, it is a good idea to take it out and recast it. It may need to be baited again, so leaving it in longer than that could be a waste of time.</string>
    <string name="getting_used_to_how_tugs_feel_will_take_some_time_as_smaller_fish_tugs_may_act_differently_but_be_the_same_strength_as_the_waves_or_the_wind_on_your_sinker_or_line_when_you_feel_a_tug_your_first_instinct_should_be_pulling_your_rod_upwards_pushing_the_hook_further_into_the_catch_this_functions_as_to_secure_the_hook_in_the_fish_reeling_in_the_line_should_not_just_be_done_with_only_the_reel_the_reel_may_not_be_strong_enough_to_pull_in_the_larger_fish_appropriate_reeling_requires_the_fisherman_to_pull_back_the_rod_and_reel_in_the_slack_created_by_the_pull_doing_this_repeatedly_ensures_the_fight_to_pull_on_the_rod_itself_and_not_the_small_reel">Getting used to how tugs feel will take some time as smaller fish tugs may act differently, but be the same strength as the waves or the wind on your sinker or line. When you feel a tug, your first instinct should be pulling your rod upwards, pushing the hook further into the catch. This functions as to secure the hook in the fish. Reeling in the line should not just be done with only the reel. The reel may not be strong enough to pull in the larger fish. Appropriate reeling requires the fisherman to pull back the rod and reel in the slack created by the pull. Doing this repeatedly ensures the fight to pull on the rod itself and not the small reel.</string>
    <string name="once_a_fish_is_caught_what_to_do_with_it_is_only_somewhat_up_to_you_releasing_it_back_is_always_an_option_but_in_order_to_keep_the_catch_some_further_identification_is_required_there_are_size_and_species_regulations_that_should_be_explained_to_you_as_you_get_your_license_that_require_you_to_release_some_fish_depending_on_their_age_determined_by_size_and_species_if_you_are_keeping_the_fish_the_appropriate_containers_should_be_accounted_for">Once a fish is caught, what to do with it is only somewhat up to you. Releasing it back is always an option, but in order to keep the catch, some further identification is required. There are size and species regulations that should be explained to you as you get your license that require you to release some fish depending on their age (determined by size) and species. If you are keeping the fish, the appropriate containers should be accounted for.</string>
    <string name="_4_decide_what_to_do_with_your_fish">4.) Decide what to do with your fish.</string>
    <string name="_3_pay_attention_to_your_wake">3. Pay Attention To Your Wake</string>
    <string name="it_s_easy_to_consider_the_water_from_only_a_fisherman_s_perspective_but_there_are_many_other_people_that_use_the_water_for_different_reasons_like_recreational_boating_skiing_swimming_or_even_just_pristine_viewing_of_the_lake_although_different_their_needs_and_goals_are_just_as_important_to_them_as_your_need_to_catch_fish_if_an_area_is_no_wake_it_s_probably_that_way_for_a_reason_if_a_landowner_asks_you_politely_to_try_and_avoid_snagging_your_lure_on_their_dock_be_respectful_we_are_fortunate_to_have_the_resources_we_do_and_understanding_other_folks_needs_will_help_you_enjoy_yourself_more_on_the_water">It’s easy to consider the water from only a fisherman’s perspective, but there are many other people that use the water for different reasons like recreational boating, skiing, swimming, or even just pristine viewing of the lake. Although different, their needs and goals are just as important to them as your need to catch fish. If an area is no wake, it’s probably that way for a reason. If a landowner asks you politely to try and avoid snagging your lure on their dock, be respectful. We are fortunate to have the resources we do, and understanding other folks needs will help you enjoy yourself more on the water.</string>
    <string name="good_fishing_etiquette_is_also_about_taking_care_of_the_resource_and_waste_not_want_not_applies_on_the_water_as_well_if_you_re_keeping_fish_only_take_what_you_can_eat_regardless_of_the_limit_if_you_re_in_a_tournament_setting_make_sure_to_take_care_of_your_fish_to_minimize_their_time_spent_out_of_the_water_and_use_a_good_quality_landing_net_to_prevent_damage_to_their_slime_coat">Good fishing etiquette is also about taking care of the resource, and waste not, want not applies on the water as well. If you’re keeping fish, only take what you can eat, regardless of the limit. If you’re in a tournament setting, make sure to take care of your fish to minimize their time spent out of the water, and use a good quality landing net to prevent damage to their slime coat.</string>
    <string name="this_is_something_that_has_become_particularly_common_among_anglers_that_haven_t_experienced_grinding_out_the_hours_it_takes_to_find_good_fishing_locations_give_other_anglers_a_wide_berth_while_on_the_water_and_ask_if_it_is_ok_to_pass_them_or_fish_in_areas_close_to_where_they_are_fishing_even_if_they_are_fishing_for_some_other_species_there_is_almost_no_scenario_where_the_fish_are_only_biting_in_one_area_so_pulling_up_on_someone_else_s_spot_will_usually_only_cause_an_ugly_confrontation">This is something that has become particularly common among anglers that haven’t experienced grinding out the hours it takes to find good fishing locations. Give other anglers a wide berth while on the water, and ask if it is ok to pass them or fish in areas close to where they are fishing – even if they are fishing for some other species. There is almost no scenario where the fish are only biting in one area, so pulling up on someone else’s spot will usually only cause an ugly confrontation.</string>
    <string name="although_no_wake_laws_are_in_place_across_many_waters_of_this_country_they_aren_t_the_only_places_to_mind_your_wake_if_you_are_in_close_proximity_to_recreational_anglers_kayakers_canoeists_or_even_people_swimming_pay_attention_and_reduce_your_speed_to_show_respect_for_their_pursuits_this_can_be_justifiably_frustrating_in_a_tournament_situation_but_remember_how_you_act_on_the_water_affects_how_folks_perceive_fishermen_as_a_whole">Although no-wake laws are in place across many waters of this country, they aren’t the only places to mind your wake. If you are in close proximity to recreational anglers, kayakers, canoeists, or even people swimming – pay attention and reduce your speed to show respect for their pursuits. This can be justifiably frustrating in a tournament situation, but remember, how you act on the water affects how folks perceive fishermen as a whole.</string>
    <string name="boat_ramps_are_busy_enough_in_the_summer_months_don_t_compound_that_by_being_an_inconsiderate_launcher_prepare_your_boat_for_launching_prior_to_moving_onto_the_ramp_and_once_loaded_quickly_move_away_from_the_crowd_to_wipe_it_down_and_prepare_it_for_the_road_if_you_re_picking_up_a_friend_or_co_angler_arrange_to_do_it_at_a_gas_station_or_nearby_lot_so_you_re_not_waiting_around_blocking_traffic">Boat ramps are busy enough in the summer months – don’t compound that by being an inconsiderate launcher. Prepare your boat for launching prior to moving onto the ramp, and once loaded, quickly move away from the crowd to wipe it down and prepare it for the road. If you’re picking up a friend or co-angler, arrange to do it at a gas station or nearby lot so you’re not waiting around blocking traffic.</string>
    <string name="this_mantra_was_originally_developed_by_the_us_forest_service_as_a_motto_for_campers_but_it_s_equally_applicable_on_the_water_try_to_minimize_your_presence_while_fishing_by_not_littering_policing_your_used_plastics_and_line_and_preventing_damage_to_the_waters_as_tempting_as_it_may_be_to_cut_branches_off_a_dead_tree_to_access_new_water_doing_so_would_remove_habitat_and_set_a_precedent_that_others_may_follow_if_it_wasn_t_there_when_you_got_on_the_water_it_shouldn_t_be_there_when_you_leave">This mantra was originally developed by the US Forest Service as a motto for campers, but it’s equally applicable on the water. Try to minimize your presence while fishing by not littering, policing your used plastics and line, and preventing damage to the waters. As tempting as it may be to cut branches off a dead tree to access new water, doing so would remove habitat and set a precedent that others may follow. If it wasn’t there when you got on the water, it shouldn’t be there when you leave.</string>
    <string name="_1_leave_no_trace">1. Leave No Trace</string>
    <string name="_2_be_a_conscientious_launcher">2. Be A Conscientious Launcher</string>
    <string name="_4_don_t_be_a_bent_rod_angler">4. Don’t Be A “Bent Rod” Angler</string>
    <string name="_5_take_care_of_your_fish">5. Take Care Of Your Fish</string>
    <string name="_6_you_re_not_the_only_one_on_the_water">6. You’re Not The Only One On The Water</string>
    <string name="bottom_trawling">Bottom Trawling</string>
    <string name="cyanide_fishing">Cyanide Fishing</string>
    <string name="dynamite_fishing">Dynamite Fishing</string>
    <string name="ghost_fishing">Ghost Fishing</string>
    <string name="many_fishing_practices_are_destructive_to_delicate_habitats_particularly_vital_fish_breeding_grounds_like_coral_reefs_and_seagrass_meadows">Many fishing practices are destructive to delicate habitats, particularly vital fish breeding grounds like coral reefs and seagrass meadows.</string>
    <string name="industrial_trawlers_once_avoided_coral_reefs_and_other_rocky_regions_of_the_ocean_floor_because_their_nets_would_snag_and_tear_but_the_introduction_of_rockhopper_trawls_in_the_1980s_changed_this_the_largest_with_heavy_rollers_over_75cm_in_diameter_are_very_powerful_capable_of_moving_boulders_weighing_25_tonnes_now_most_of_the_ocean_floor_can_be_trawled_down_to_a_depth_of_2_000m_in_heavily_fished_areas_around_coral_seamounts_off_southern_australia_for_example_90_of_the_surfaces_where_coral_used_to_grow_are_now_bare_rock_like_removing_forest_removing_this_cover_decreases_the_area_available_for_marine_species_to_live_and_thrive_in">Industrial trawlers once avoided coral reefs and other rocky regions of the ocean floor because their nets would snag and tear. But the introduction of rockhopper trawls in the 1980s changed this. The largest, with heavy rollers over 75cm in diameter, are very powerful, capable of moving boulders weighing 25 tonnes. Now, most of the ocean floor can be trawled down to a depth of 2,000m. In heavily fished areas around coral seamounts off southern Australia for example, 90% of the surfaces where coral used to grow are now bare rock. Like removing forest, removing this cover decreases the area available for marine species to live and thrive in.</string>
    <string name="in_this_technique_fishers_squirt_sodium_cyanide_into_the_water_to_stun_fish_without_killing_them_making_them_easy_to_catch_cyanide_fishing_on_coral_reefs_began_in_the_1960s_to_supply_the_international_aquarium_trade_but_since_the_early_1980s_supplying_live_reef_fish_for_the_restaurants_of_hong_kong_singapore_and_increasingly_mainland_china_is_a_much_more_profitable_business_some_20_000_tonnes_of_live_fish_are_eaten_annually_in_the_restaurants_of_hong_kong_and_for_every_live_fish_caught_using_cyanide_a_square_metre_of_their_coral_reef_home_is_killed">In this technique, fishers squirt sodium cyanide into the water to stun fish without killing them, making them easy to catch. Cyanide fishing on coral reefs began in the 1960s to supply the international aquarium trade. But since the early 1980s, supplying live reef fish for the restaurants of Hong Kong, Singapore, and, increasingly, mainland China is a much more profitable business. Some 20,000 tonnes of live fish are eaten annually in the restaurants of Hong Kong - and for every live fish caught using cyanide, a square metre of their coral reef home is killed.</string>
    <string name="in_this_technique_dynamite_or_other_explosives_are_set_off_under_water_the_dead_fish_floating_to_the_surface_are_then_simply_scooped_up_the_explosives_completely_destroy_the_underwater_environment_leaving_it_as_rubble_dynamite_fishing_has_contributed_to_massive_destruction_of_for_example_southeast_asian_coral_reefs_over_the_past_20_years">In this technique, dynamite or other explosives are set off under water. The dead fish floating to the surface are then simply scooped up. The explosives completely destroy the underwater environment, leaving it as rubble. Dynamite fishing has contributed to massive destruction of, for example, Southeast Asian coral reefs over the past 20 years.</string>
    <string name="ghost_fishing_occurs_when_fishing_gear_is_lost_or_abandoned_at_sea_the_gear_can_continue_to_catch_fish_dolphins_whales_turtles_and_other_creatures_as_it_drifts_through_the_water_and_after_it_becomes_snagged_on_the_seabed_when_driftnets_were_used_on_the_high_seas_an_estimated_1_000km_of_ghost_nets_were_released_each_year_into_the_north_pacific_ocean_alone">Ghost fishing occurs when fishing gear is lost or abandoned at sea. The gear can continue to catch fish, dolphins, whales, turtles, and other creatures as it drifts through the water and after it becomes snagged on the seabed. When driftnets were used on the High Seas, an estimated 1,000km of ghost nets were released each year into the North Pacific Ocean alone.</string>
    <string name="nichol_glenn_s_fu_e">Nichol Glenn S. Fuñe</string>
    <string name="marvin_jake_a_macato">Marvin Jake A. Macato</string>
    <string name="_2015081045_ust_ics_mygbiz_com">2015081045@ust.ics-mygbiz.com</string>
    <string name="_4it_e_it_automation">4IT-E IT Automation</string>
    <string name="_2015082852_ust_ics_mygbiz_com">2015082852@ust.ics-mygbiz.com</string>
    <string name="references">References:</string>
    <string name="https_www_wikihow_com_fish_for_beginners">https://www.wikihow.com/Fish-(for-Beginners)</string>
    <string name="https_shopkarls_com_blog_fishing_etiquette_101_6_rules_for_respect_on_the_water">https://shopkarls.com/blog/fishing-etiquette-101-6-rules-for-respect-on-the-water/</string>
    <string name="https_wwf_panda_org_our_work_oceans_problems_destructive_fishing">https://wwf.panda.org/our_work/oceans/problems/destructive_fishing/</string>
    <string name="fishing_rod">Fishing Rod</string>
    <string name="fishing_reel">Fishing Reel</string>
    <string name="fishing_line">Fishing Line</string>
    <string name="bait">Bait</string>
    <string name="bobbers">Bobbers</string>
    <string name="sinkers">Sinkers</string>
    <string name="needle_nose_pliers">Needle Nose Pliers</string>
    <string name="sunscreen">Sunscreen</string>
    <string name="first_aid_kit">First Aid Kit</string>
    <string name="line_cutters">Line Cutters</string>
    <string name="lures">Lures</string>
    <string name="hooks">Hooks</string>
    <string name="https_www_artofmanliness_com_articles_10_things_every_mans_fishing_tackle_box_needs">https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/10-things-every-mans-fishing-tackle-box-needs/</string>
</resources>
